<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terraform on OpenVERS</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/tags/terraform/</link><description>Recent content in Terraform on OpenVERS</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terraform Backend</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/aws/terraform_backend/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/aws/terraform_backend/</guid><description>Terrafrom Backend with AWS Using AWS as the backend for Terraform state is another versatile option for managing infrastructure as code. By storing Terraform state in an AWS S3 bucket, teams can take advantage of AWS&amp;rsquo;s robust security features, such as encryption at rest and in transit, access controls, and versioning. Additionally, AWS S3 provides a highly durable and available storage solution, ensuring that Terraform state is always accessible and up-to-date.</description></item><item><title>Terraform Backend</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/terraform_backend/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/terraform_backend/</guid><description>Terraform Backend with Azure Using Azure as the backend for Terraform state is a robust and versatile option for managing infrastructure as code. By storing Terraform state in an Azure Blob Storage container, teams can leverage Azure&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive security features, including encryption at rest and in transit, access controls via Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) and Role-Based Access Control (RBAC), and versioning capabilities. Azure Blob Storage offers a highly durable and available storage solution, ensuring that Terraform state is consistently accessible and protected.</description></item><item><title>Terraform Backend</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/terraform_backend/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/terraform_backend/</guid><description>Terraform Backend with Google Cloud Storage Using Google Cloud Storage (GCS) as the backend for Terraform state is a robust and common practice for managing infrastructure as code on GCP. By storing Terraform state in a GCS bucket, teams can benefit from Google Cloud&amp;rsquo;s strong security features, such as encryption at rest and in transit, fine-grained access control with IAM, and object versioning for state history and recovery. GCS provides a highly durable and available storage solution, ensuring that Terraform state is consistently accessible.</description></item><item><title>Terraform.io</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/terraform_io/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/terraform_io/</guid><description>Terraform is a powerful infrastructure-as-code (IaC) tool that enables users to automate the provisioning, management, and scaling of infrastructure across various cloud providers such as AWS, Azure, and Google Cloud, as well as on-premise environments. With its declarative configuration language, Terraform allows users to define infrastructure in reusable code that can be versioned and shared, ensuring consistency and reducing manual errors. One of its key capabilities is the use of state files, which track the infrastructure&amp;rsquo;s current state, enabling Terraform to apply only necessary changes when updating resources.</description></item></channel></rss>