<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GCP on OpenVERS</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/tags/gcp/</link><description>Recent content in GCP on OpenVERS</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/tags/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Account Setup</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/new_account_setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/new_account_setup/</guid><description>Setup New Account Creating a Google Cloud Platform (GCP) presence starts with a Google Account. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, you can create one for free. You&amp;rsquo;ll then create a &amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo; within GCP to organize your resources. Billing is managed through a &amp;ldquo;Billing Account&amp;rdquo; linked to your projects. More details can be found at the GCP Get Started page. It&amp;rsquo;s critical to implement robust security measures from the outset to protect your GCP resources and data from unauthorized access and potential breaches.</description></item><item><title>Terraform Backend</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/terraform_backend/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/terraform_backend/</guid><description>Terraform Backend with Google Cloud Storage Using Google Cloud Storage (GCS) as the backend for Terraform state is a robust and common practice for managing infrastructure as code on GCP. By storing Terraform state in a GCS bucket, teams can benefit from Google Cloud&amp;rsquo;s strong security features, such as encryption at rest and in transit, fine-grained access control with IAM, and object versioning for state history and recovery. GCS provides a highly durable and available storage solution, ensuring that Terraform state is consistently accessible.</description></item><item><title>OpenID Connect</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/openid_connect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/openid_connect/</guid><description>OpenID Connect (OIDC) with GitHub Actions and GCP Workload Identity Federation Google Cloud&amp;rsquo;s Workload Identity Federation allows identities from external OpenID Connect (OIDC) providers, like GitHub Actions, to impersonate Google Cloud service accounts. This enables your GitHub Actions workflows to securely access GCP resources without needing to manage or store long-lived service account keys in GitHub. Instead, workflows obtain short-lived access tokens, enhancing security and simplifying credential management for CI/CD pipelines.</description></item><item><title>Google Cloud Platform (GCP)</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/</guid><description>GCP (Google Cloud Platform) is a comprehensive suite of cloud computing services offered by Google. It provides a wide array of services, including computing, storage, databases, big data analytics, machine learning, and more. GCP enables data practitioners to build, deploy, and manage applications and workloads in a flexible, scalable, and secure environment. When setting up GCP for the first time, focusing on security is paramount for data practitioners to ensure the confidentiality and integrity of their data and applications.</description></item></channel></rss>