<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New Account on OpenVERS</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/categories/new-account/</link><description>Recent content in New Account on OpenVERS</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/categories/new-account/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Account Setup</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/aws/new_account_setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/aws/new_account_setup/</guid><description>Setup New Account Creating an AWS account can be done free of charge. More details about registering with AWS can be found at their New Account Instructions web page. We also need to keep in mind securing protective measures against our newly created users to protect our resources and data from possible breaches and mailicous actors, and therefore we follow some elementary guidelines documented by AWS for securing new user setup.</description></item><item><title>Account Setup</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/new_account_setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/new_account_setup/</guid><description>Setup New Azure Account Creating an Azure account can often start with a free tier offering. Similar to other cloud providers, establishing robust security measures from the beginning is crucial to protect your Azure resources, data, and identities from unauthorized access and potential threats. We will follow Azure&amp;rsquo;s recommended practices for a secure initial setup.
Azure Resource Groups Azure resource groups are a fundamental concept in Azure to organize resource into specific use case groups for cost and monitoring purposes.</description></item><item><title>Account Setup</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/new_account_setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/gcp/new_account_setup/</guid><description>Setup New Account Creating a Google Cloud Platform (GCP) presence starts with a Google Account. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have one, you can create one for free. You&amp;rsquo;ll then create a &amp;ldquo;Project&amp;rdquo; within GCP to organize your resources. Billing is managed through a &amp;ldquo;Billing Account&amp;rdquo; linked to your projects. More details can be found at the GCP Get Started page. It&amp;rsquo;s critical to implement robust security measures from the outset to protect your GCP resources and data from unauthorized access and potential breaches.</description></item></channel></rss>