<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Lake on OpenVERS</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/categories/data-lake/</link><description>Recent content in Data Lake on OpenVERS</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/categories/data-lake/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Ingestion &amp; Data Lake</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/data_ingestion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/data_ingestion/</guid><description>What is Data Ingestion? The initial process of collecting and transporting data from various sources into a storage or processing system, such as a data warehouse, data lake, or analytics platform. It is the foundational step in building data pipelines, enabling organizations to centralize, analyze, and derive insights from their data. Common terminology in this area include:
Data Ingestion: The general process of moving data from source systems to a target system.</description></item><item><title>AWS | Data Ingestion &amp; Data Lake</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/data_ingestion/aws/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/data_ingestion/aws/</guid><description>Infrastructure This deployment provisions a cloud-native, event-driven data ingestion pipeline on AWS, following the medallion architecture (Bronze/Silver/Gold zones) as described in the architecture overview. The infrastructure is modular and reusable, leveraging the Terraform modules found in AWS HTTP Trigger repo.
S3 Buckets S3 Cloud Storage buckets are created to form the medallion landing zones for our Data Lake. The buckets are configured with the following minumal security and retention requirements:</description></item></channel></rss>