<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microsoft Azure on OpenVERS</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Microsoft Azure on OpenVERS</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Account Setup</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/new_account_setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/new_account_setup/</guid><description>Setup New Azure Account Creating an Azure account can often start with a free tier offering. Similar to other cloud providers, establishing robust security measures from the beginning is crucial to protect your Azure resources, data, and identities from unauthorized access and potential threats. We will follow Azure&amp;rsquo;s recommended practices for a secure initial setup.
Azure Resource Groups Azure resource groups are a fundamental concept in Azure to organize resource into specific use case groups for cost and monitoring purposes.</description></item><item><title>Terraform Backend</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/terraform_backend/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/terraform_backend/</guid><description>Terraform Backend with Azure Using Azure as the backend for Terraform state is a robust and versatile option for managing infrastructure as code. By storing Terraform state in an Azure Blob Storage container, teams can leverage Azure&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive security features, including encryption at rest and in transit, access controls via Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) and Role-Based Access Control (RBAC), and versioning capabilities. Azure Blob Storage offers a highly durable and available storage solution, ensuring that Terraform state is consistently accessible and protected.</description></item><item><title>OpenID Connect</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/openid_connect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/azure/openid_connect/</guid><description>OpenID Connect (OIDC) with GitHub Actions and Azure Workload Identity Federation Azure&amp;rsquo;s Workload identity federation allows external OpenID Connect (OIDC) providers, like GitHub Actions, to authenticate to Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) and obtain access tokens for Azure resources. This is achieved by configuring a federated identity credential on an Azure AD application registration or user-assigned managed identity. This enables your GitHub Actions workflows to securely access Azure resources without needing to manage or store long-lived secrets (like client secrets or certificates) in GitHub.</description></item></channel></rss>