<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Setup on OpenVERS</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud Setup on OpenVERS</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Github</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/github/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/github/</guid><description>Having a GitHub organization is crucial for Data Practioners and Businesses because it centralizes and manages code repositories under one cohesive structure. It allows for better collaboration by giving multiple users access to shared projects while maintaining control over permissions and visibility. Instead of individual repositories scattered across personal accounts, a Github Organization allows projects to be consolidated in a secure and professional environment. This structure is essential for large projects where multiple contributors, such as developers, designers, and project managers, need to collaborate efficiently while ensuring that intellectual property and source code are well-organized and protected.</description></item><item><title>Terraform.io</title><link>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/terraform_io/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openvers.github.io/docs_blog/docs/cloud_setup/terraform_io/</guid><description>Terraform is a powerful infrastructure-as-code (IaC) tool that enables users to automate the provisioning, management, and scaling of infrastructure across various cloud providers such as AWS, Azure, and Google Cloud, as well as on-premise environments. With its declarative configuration language, Terraform allows users to define infrastructure in reusable code that can be versioned and shared, ensuring consistency and reducing manual errors. One of its key capabilities is the use of state files, which track the infrastructure&amp;rsquo;s current state, enabling Terraform to apply only necessary changes when updating resources.</description></item></channel></rss>